It's time for a new puzzle of the month.
This one comes from a problem on the 2024 British Math Olympiad.
The setup is to have 64 sugar cubes arranged in a 4x4x4 block.
Each cube is either white, blue, or brown.
Your challenge is to prove that you can find 6 pairs of cubes,
such that all 12 individual cubes involved are the same color,
and such that the lengths of these six lines,
the lines connecting the centers of the cubes in a given pair, are all the same.
And that's 6 equal distances.
So just to be clear, you have to show that no matter what the allocation of colors
to these 64 different spots in our big 4x4x4 cube is, you can always do this.
You can always find 12 little cubes of the same color that can be divided into 6
different pairs such that there's a common distance between the centers of each pair.